all right Jordan thanks for meeting with
me thanks for your time I know you're
super busy these days I just wanted to
hear what you're up to in the game B or
like now that you're not in the game B
Facebook group and I wanted to update
you on what I've learned - what I've
been doing the last I think it was in
like six months since we since we
chatted last and sure all I can give you
just a little bit cuz frankly some of
its not uh I can't really share it
publicly but maybe the best way of
saying it is doing game B and what I
mean by that is finding or using
existing high trust relationships so
people who are in a position where they
can introduce me to somebody through a
very high quality first person
relationship that is relevant so
relevance realization x high trust
having conversations to find out what's
going on so we're talking about this
sort of the coronavirus and all the
other stuff like finance and education
the whole bit yeah finding out if you
imagine there's a big social graph
that's forming around the problem domain
there's more or less two moves that are
happening one move is improving our
sense making about the nature of the
problem to me but what is it what are
the questions and what are the kind of
the questions relate to each other you
know for example over the past month
there's been a recognition that this
concept called medical system
overwhelmed it's a problem to remain
like it's a very specific kind of thing
there's a whole bunch of questions that
have to be asked about that domain there
are other problems having to do with
with epidemiology how do we model the
spread of disease and how do we get
those models better and better there's a
whole bunch of people are focused on
that problem to me okay
so being aware of the problem domains
and then second move is forming the
network of people in relationships and
ideally high trust relationships and
high competence relationships so it's a
thing every day okay I and with the
people who I'm currently aware of and
connected on are working on these things
right here I now just discovered a you
are part of a network over here they're
working on these things how do we create
the cross connections between these two
so that you guys can stop working on
that because we've actually got that
covered pretty good
but you guys have got this thing over
here that we knew is a problem we
haven't been thought about and frankly
you're probably better to us than this
so we're just gonna drop in let you take
that over and creating the network
connections to base it to work through
the the bottlenecks and the log jams
that are caused either by simply being
unaware or by the difference between
institutions I game a and game B
oftentimes the problems you run into or
that gaming institutions either can't
see well or can't make effective choices
I mean simple things like my
administrative process for engaging and
procurement requires that I have net
90-day payment and the person who has
the thing I want won't take NIT a 90 day
payment and I can't modify that because
I'm in a gaming institution where I have
to go up to the vice president all this
kind of crap right so how do you
actually start creating game b-style
infrastructures human meshwork stuff in
between all the nodes that need to
happen and built on the right stuff
right it's not built on high quality
high competence high trust relationships
so getting on the phone and saying who
do you know who you know you like spend
time in the in the foxhole with that you
know that they will do what they say
with high integrity and if they're
effective and what they're doing and how
do we actually orient them into a place
where they're capacitors are most needed
and where they're able to have the most
they themselves are able to perceive the
most possibility of adding value so the
self organization the self-organizing
collective intelligence around an
increasing sense making in the
underlying problem domains is what I'm
doing nice I like it I'm glad I'm glad
there's people focusing on that we
desperately need it
I've been upfront to it from a different
side of that we're figuring out how to
bring people together to have an
effective conversation and to bring it
into the world I in the game be space
and tried many a thing and some of it
has come to crickets and no one's taking
me up on it and then other things have
been more successful and I'm trying to
go down and be a Vanina sitter that are
more successful of course yeah so the
idea cafe was my baby when I first came
in and so we've been having a few of
those we just have a weekly one for game
B and that's just enjoyable it's
enjoyable people have a space they can
have a conversation that has some
structure around it but it's fallen by
the wayside because it's just not as
important
other projects which are we become its
Bentley and my brother Adriel and I and
yo Nez sometimes where who created
together Tec and we're trying to kind of
figure out the meta project of projects
for getting bees so because that is what
doesn't get Curtis is people have their
own project that they're passionate
about so getting those people to come
together and say how can we create Omni
with solutions that empower all of our
projects right create the marketing the
finance how do we create that but
unfortunately although we've done
project rate Z and I think you left
after project crazies I think you
probably know what project crazy knows
or we just focus on one person's project
and we crowdsource solutions for an hour
for them based on what they want to have
happen yep there was no shortage of
people who of course wanted there's
their own project raised but there was a
shortage of people showing up to raise
other people's projects so it's
basically been lady at really night
raising other girls project so should
enjoyable cuz I love that I love
listening to people's ideas and helping
them create things that I don't actually
have to do the work on right yes you can
see other things on other people's
projects and so we're figuring that out
together how do we get more people there
we have the Facebook group unfortunately
Facebook's algorithm doesn't really work
to to empower individuals and groups and
so people don't see it and we're trying
to work around that but we're figuring
it out together
and during this process I want to be
having generative conversations and so
after project raising and what that
looks like I came up with solution
raising which we've had six of them and
it's an hour long conversation broken
into three parts we spend 15 minutes
talking about what is currently done in
that space so we've talked about
education we've talked about
transportation we talked about of
infectious diseases we've talked about
food and so any may be come up with like
what's currently done that's usually
what we talk about so we only spend 15
minutes on it because we kind understand
what the problem with food is and its
fragility then we spend 15 minutes
talking about what our version of an
ideal future would look like and they
don't need to match you know Internet
vote on them it's like what would my
ideal food system look like in a world
however long in the future I need that
to be for it to be feasible for my mind
and then we spend half an hour talking
about something we could create right
now if we had 10,000 people at $100,000
so not some
we're like we're gonna feed everyone on
the planet how if we had 10,000 people
who wanted to be fed what would be
something we could create that would
help them in that process and after six
of them every single one has generated
an amazing solution an amazing thing
that we could create and so the next
thing I'm looking at doing is creating a
solution or a Zenon solution raising how
do we actually find 10,000 people how do
we actually because these conversations
have only been three to five people they
haven't been a hundred people how do we
have this conversation with a hundred
people where each one is having their
own little for Petersons table kind of
like the idea cafe and then we submit
them and vote on which one's the best it
is not the best way and so actually
figuring out how do we now move forward
with the solution amazing how do we
create these ideas together and then how
do we actually generate them actually
yeah yeah so can I say some stuff there
yeah I was thinking about exactly this
issue right before this call and the
last bits last piece yeah so let's see
so what you want to be able to do is
find a way to have this thing grow in
almost like a rhizomatic fashion the way
that uh mushroom mycelium grows we'd
like to be able to do as habit so that
the the content of the conversation its
packaged in such a way they can be
disseminated peer to peer and activate
people to be to come at it in a certain
and I think it's probably a set of waves
the field Smith is that concentric
circles like you said there's a a
certain almost like a design team who
are you familiar at the Charles purses
epistemology yeah you know like when you
play when you play you build a puzzle
you take all the puzzle pieces and you
drop them out of the box and the very
beginning that there's this first moment
where you really don't even have a clue
exactly what's going on you just kind of
know there's a puzzle to be dealt with
and then there's a period of time where
you're beginning the process of finding
the edges and kind of getting the
outside of and getting a sense of what
the pattern is that you have this pop
like okay now I'm actually in the
process of assembling the puzzle and
then there's a period of time where we
actually now have a pretty good sense of
the puzzle you're just putting pieces in
place but you kind of know that the end
is near I mean you don't know exactly
how close it is does the end he tells
that first in a second is in third this
so the face of firstness which feels
like it's a little bit of the first two
phases you've been talking about is the
design phase it's a design when you
don't really know you kind of have a
general sense of the domain I'm solving
a puzzle right I'm not building a
bicycle or trying to figure out how to
raise a child which are different kinds
of puzzles and you bring some people in
there who maybe have relevant some
relevant perspective some relevant
expertise ideally some to know highly
divergent perspectives so you get a lot
of richness in the design process and
they try to do something like getting it
something in the direction of firstness
some notion that has got you know
something like call it 15% of the
question domain has been aha and most of
it may be maybe they meet some of the
most meaningful questions have been
surfaced maybe not necessarily answered
then you have the second wave of folks
who come in and they're basically not
there to do a whole lot of cracking open
the frame but they're mostly there to
make sure to add more meat to them to
the start to the structure ask more
specific questions modify questions that
haven't been asked the right way and to
build a little more framework around it
so you get to something like on the
order of like it's 85% this is a viable
solution that this could work it's not
all the way but it could work then you
got the third piece right the third
piece is where you're doing that last
mile which is you know from Pareto rule
the last 20% still 80% of the work a lot
of details have to be filled in to make
sure you're uncovering situations that
you didn't see they can be able to be a
problem but a lot of us also actually
building out on a p2p basis having
conversations with people to enroll that
1000 once you got to 1,000 the 10,000
will come automatically
but the 1000 is the product is a process
that third stage and how do you find
those people how do you find people who
are sitting in the middle of this domain
but are not yet connected to your
network and our leaders right they're
there they they cannot help but be
leaders because that's just who they are
their disposition their attitude their
motivation their with other people
relate to them so they see this design
and hopefully you've done a good job so
when they see their son like yeah that's
a good good design I get it that makes
sense
I'd like to see that and you you begin
the process of enrolling those people in
that loop that larger circle and having
conversations that that just kind of has
them feel heard right they you want them
to actually have a sense of the thing
that I'm holding that maybe isn't in
here is now in here
and now I can now now I am no longer
equivocal now I can actually what would
it take for you to move from being
interested to being committed in this
what would make it a whole solution that
your wholeness but everything you care
about is in this at least with regard to
this domain and we're not trying to
solve all the problems in the universe
but within this domain you feel really
good about it okay great
can we find a finally a thing where we
get wholeness a closure where we've got
a people around it that have enough and
then it's just a very simple that last
step is very simple but you have each of
those thousand people say okay get ten
people you know they've been talking to
you for a while about this and if all
you do is you tell them this is the
right solution I'd like you to sign up
and this is what it takes and maybe it's
just a little skin in the game because
ten people times $10 ten thousand times
ten dollars a hundred thousand dollars
exactly and if you got a good design
it's been been vetted and socialized as
it goes to this process and you have a
thousand people who are leaders in their
sub domain who care about this thing and
they validated it themselves I think
you're kind of done so the hard part is
actually each of those steps and it
sounds like you've got you've gone
through step one and step two to the
level you've got some of these things
and figuring out that third one is funny
now you know you did the matter or I'm
just I'm doing the matter you're doing
the thing about the thing everybody
you're interacting with there's you're
doing it both from the point of view of
a concrete domain say like food we
actually also doing at a meta domain
which is how do we do this thing how do
we do this first and second
assertiveness process so all of
everybody's probably engaged right now
is probably looking at both a couple of
things that came up for me I'm not sure
what I'm about to say is relevant
because I think there may be I'm
operating in a very different
environment right now sit which has
different tensors on it what I can say
is there's certain kinds of dispositions
and certain kinds of relationships that
sorry it's very hard for me to keep this
phone strain you turn it maybe it's like
a whole little easier there we go
there's just a lot easier to do things
with there's just people who are capable
of having conversations and have
disciplines of mind and their
disposition so they hear what's being
said and they don't grab a conversation
to try to load it with their own
preferences
start just meandering off in the middle
of nowhere because it's what is in their
mind right now the people who have just
a certain unless you knew what's
happening I'm focusing on what's being
talked about right now I have an
internal capacity to not put signal or
noise into the environment and if I make
an agreement it's an agreement like I'm
not I'm not going to fail to do what I
just said I have integrity and my
capacity to make agreements and if you
build this kind of thing out of those
people it's it's very real because if
they if they've said they're gonna do it
they're gonna and that tells you a lot
unfortunately there's a whole lot of
people particularly people who are
attracted to it's call it change making
or to idea space who don't have those
characteristics and that's so and I
think that makes sense because there's a
necessity like oak trait openness has
you need to have trade openness to
consider firstness to consider brand new
ideas yeah just think think outside the
box that's a whole different policy the
problem one of the problems I've found
is that people who have that trait that
are so valuable in the first phase and
they're being really problematic in the
second phase because once the shiny
objects not so shiny anymore they
started going off looking for the next
shiny thing and to be perfectly frank
quite often their ability to make an
agreement and commit to it goes down so
it's almost like a demographic shift we
actually want to have the designer phase
be people who are ready willing and able
to think outside the box but somewhere
in that second page you want to start
rolling that we have a high
conscientiousness and they're gonna be
kind of they'll call a lot
because when they make an agreement they
they're committing to it so they're
gonna be the guys are actually gonna
crack open the idea and say yeah access
smells like to me it's this thing I
don't know what you guys are talking us
you actually
you know you get pushed by those people
and that's good because then you know
you have a better design and and then if
you get them enrolled then you've got
like this the the folks who make things
happen that make any sense yeah
absolutely I mean it's a little weird
because I might be one of those like I'm
like right I kind of like the shiny
object and I really like having the
conversations that are generative and I
don't even have the capacity necessarily
to do the actual physical work like
actual physical world kind of digging
ditches I'd be able to plan where they
need to be dug but I can't actually do
that physical work that's a bigger
right people who can know and so it's
about finding that forming that
connections form of that connection
honorably is crucial because those
people the people who dig ditches on the
one hand they're digging the
ditch and they don't want to be told to
dig the wrong ditch because that's a lot
of work and they don't know if they've
noticed over the past 10,000 years it's
a real big habit of the folks on top to
be very flippant about digging ditches
because they don't carry the burden of
it there's a real powerful capacity if
you can recreate those lines of trust
vertically and then they are vertical I
mean in the sense the person on the
ground is on the ground the person in
the skies in the sky I don't mean in
terms of importance quite the opposite I
think the importance is very everybody's
got their role to play but creating that
and it's non-trivial because it's a
dispositional man it's actually think
about it also politically can we do that
politically because it's true they're to
the great sort that happened over the
latter half of the 20th century where we
were no longer bound to extended
families in the place that we were born
because we could move and in fact
because we in fact as many as it's
needed to move because the jobs were
better elsewhere whether it was leaving
the small town to go to the city or was
leaving the family go to the university
or now in the modern era we could just
communicate with people over virtual
environments maybe talking to people
around us has actually exacerbated that
severing and were the people who have
more in the direction of trade openness
gravitate more towards exciting visceral
new there's attracted to new they like
new and so they tend to go to places
where new happens to be and hang out
with other people who like new stuffs
it's been less time and interacting with
people who are more about trade
conscientiousness so you get these
actual device in the device actually end
up being dispositional device they even
become loaded political divides because
they have different contexts different
Spearin PSA's and different expectations
of what right choice looks like and then
of course the political divides become
resentments and then resentments become
conflicts so if you can find a way and I
certainly am participating in this
myself quite a bit but to reconnect
those things that's the fabric out of
which reality is made is to get the
people who have the dispositions
need to be on the same team these teams
were built by evolution and we didn't
make him up as humans evolution actually
said ok tribe you're going to have six
of these kind of folks and 15 of these
kinds of folks and
two of these in one of these that's a
good chunk that group of people can
solve problems that groups of people can
get things done but also think outside
the box and can plan effectively and
make sure everybody's heard like all the
different aspects and capacities so it's
creating this sort of cross-functional
and by functional and literally
dispositional teams and figuring out how
to get those teams to be coherent with
each other in spite of their
pre-existing now now where we are to
pre-existing culture war conflicts they
are built in individual personal life
experience resentments there are
ideological frameworks and semantic code
commitments there are actual life
experience differentials and then their
biological differentials at the level of
disposition like that's a lot of
distance between them we're gonna have
to cover all that distance to actually
ground things so the right elements are
in place to really really do big stuff
yeah sorry so that's that's uh something
I have to say about that yeah I
appreciate that I don't know if I got it
all but I can watch the replay see see
what I got but ya know it's a lot of
what I what I have to deal with and work
with is that like we have conflict we
have personality conflicts at the same
time a lot of people are focusing on
getting rid of them are working not even
really working with them whereas I think
like right now during this Cove in
nineteen thing we can see how the left
and the right have very different
first-order values but we're actually
much more similar than we are different
like the left is like close the border
close the border and the right is like
so we need universal basic income
because how do we pay for things it's
like even the left and I'm also like
close the border all open borders but
not turn in a pandemic like close the
city is closed let's figure this out
yeah and so to be able to look at we
have different values when I don't get
to decide on what your values are but if
we can find a common goal we don't need
to necessarily agree on the value like
if what we're doing is solving food most
of us can agree that we want to eat and
that we want other people to eat so how
do we get people fed instead of a green
on are we gonna go vegan are we gonna
like it's like I don't care how do we
get people fed how do we make sure
there's enough calories and how do we
make sure you can
well it's interesting so it's funny
because it's well let's take this take
that conversation there's two pieces
Tuesday just pop in my head as you were
saying it so what is this dish that
we're gonna go vegan and what I want to
do is I wanted to distinguish our our
values from our ends and Daniel is
smacking burger and I had this
conversation all the time because he's
vegan and I'm not right now he's not
that he's not the kind of vegan he's not
like radix weaken but so we talked about
it and at the bottom and it's more like
okay where do where do our values align
because we're our values align we can
actually get stuff done and then we can
work forward so let's not fight about
where our value is different that's
worry about where our values align where
they align our factory farms got to go
that's easy
I'm done you don't have to go fine great
animal testing great this dudes
give her that too it's a bad idea
doesn't work scientifically I mean as a
holdat so we can actually take a whole
bunch of things like where do our values
align kind of work our way back find
that place where the values are actually
synergistic and that what happens is you
get the real power because I come to my
perspective on the basis of my values in
my life experience which means I've got
something that I see something that I
can ground he's doing the same thing
okay so if there's a place where we have
a shared shared of values of Lineman
then what happens is that our
differentials of life experience give us
much more capacity to actually make
sense of that environment and we can
actually then create a program that will
be much more more robust it's more
carefully thought through and more
likely to be successful because more
people it'll make sense to yes so that's
that's powerful right if you can pull
that off but it's crucial it's like this
guy Joe Adelman I guess you may know
where I've heard of he he did a lot of
work on this back got about 10 years ago
where he noticed that and this I think
is now known as known in scientific
literature that people are quite poor at
being able to distinguish between what
they think they want and what they
actually want so even simple stuff like
I'm thirsty
but I want a candy bar because I haven't
actually built high quality sensitivity
to my real underlying experience so I've
just kind of got a body sensitivity of
need and then my brain just
short-circuits to junk food because I
got bad habits we got a lot of them were
really really bad it actually get
finding out what our wants are and we
actually grab a whole bunch of things
out that they don't said of or I'm
thirsty and I want a coke that's even
better it's even more straight to the
point my body's saying I'm thirsty what
I do is I grab a coke because I've kind
of trained myself to match those two
even though it's not a good match so
actually quite bad at mashing what we
want was what we think we want and we're
even worse imagine what we need was what
we want and so in that case is something
like how's this me see if I can put
concretions makes it make no sense
alright so I'm I'm hungry so I think I
want a lunchable but what I need is
nutrition and so I have to actually
think back to recognize oh I need
nutrition and while I and while I'm I
noticed that my one is hunger I actually
have to be much more careful about
noticing what is the nutrition really
require here is it more carbs or maybe
not maybe that's like Seth I'm still not
quite there what is it that I actually
needed the lower levels so we have to
actually work our way back I'm saying
this in the same context in the notion
of values differentials that slow down
if you've chosen the artifact of
satisfying the values of not harming
other sentient beings or even the deeper
value of caring you have a deep value of
caring and the almost I have a
subsidiary valuing want of not harming
other sentient beings and then you have
a notion of how to satisfy that one the
form of veganism know what that stack is
like because we get all the way down to
caring yeah I care too I share that
value I share the value of caring now
okay you now have the want of not harm
all sentient beings I'm gonna say well
does that include like gnats and ticks
cuz I don't know sure that I share that
with you let's keep working back right
we're gonna get a point where my value
of caring your value of caring will
manifest as a shared set of wants then
we can start collaborating on the thing
at the very end it was how do we satisfy
that yeah that's a powerful technique if
you can do it because it
helps people slow down and separate in
their own mind because we often get very
confused about that we actually tend to
flip it thinking very attached to the
wheat means of satisfaction as opposed
to the actual source of value yeah it's
definitely a difficult I mean I have a
slightly different take on that people
don't know what the how they that
they're they don't know what they want
the best way for them to know that they
don't know what they want is somewhat to
give them what they want right like I'll
be happy when I'm in a relationship we
could just make them in a relationship
they would know that that actually
doesn't equal happiness you're still you
in that relationship but there still
needs to be a certain amount because
then you're in that relationship you're
like that's a wrong relationship I need
this other perfect relationship and
there's always that you have to have
some amount of awareness to just know
whether you're happy in it to be able to
do actually this wasn't the solution and
it just kind of drill down into the
relationship itself like relationships
are the best crucible for the
conversation we're having you know how
often does it happen well your partner
in a relationship claims that so in my
case she in your case I don't know she
were he another clue
so my partner she may say that she wants
X whatever it is right yeah but after
really deliberating on it you know come
down to it's like oh she wants to feel
hurt at the end of the day that's
actually what she wants and when she
feels her like a whole energy level goes
down and then it turns out that X was an
artifact not really the thing but there
is the thing Y there's a thing over here
that we can actually get to but until
you actually get to the deep the deep
stuff where the Energy's coming up you
can't actually get to them to the and
frankly oftentimes very easy thing that
if you just both put your mind until you
can actually resolve so that that
happens all the time like we we take the
energy and instead of listening to what
the energy is in its depth we put all
that energy out here in some object then
we get very attached to that object as
if it's going to be the thing that
solves the problem and makes the problem
worse because it's not working and so
the energy just keeps building up yes
yes absolutely and dealing with things
at that level as well yeah I was I was
like the fact that that is big heavy
sort of giant things that we're dealing
with can I've always
be grounded in the very simple stuff
because it's it's all built of the same
material yeah yeah it's grounding this
is a very like there's only right now
will our world is a little bit
interesting it's very interesting we
live in very interesting times watching
different people fall apart in different
ways and watching different
organizations fall apart in different
ways and realizing what is there are
things that are absolutely needed in our
society we need food we need connection
we need a lot of things to happen but we
don't there's also a lot of people who
are about to find out that their job is
not needed in any way shape or form
either within their corporation or their
corporation entirely as I needed to
functional society and that's gonna come
with a lot of mental and emotional
issues and that people are still
important just because your job got
eliminated in your position and possibly
your profession got eliminated but it's
gonna feel like you got eliminated but
you did not you're still important still
have everything to give in fact now you
get to find out what you are beyond a
lawyer an engineer a doctor clearly all
those things yeah so given your giving
your nom nom de plume why don't you ever
read the essay I wrote called the coming
great transition I don't know because
I'm not very good at remembering titles
and I don't read a lot because of my in
this in this timeline but in the I
talked about exactly that issues we
almost have these two worlds the world
of scarcity where if your job goes away
suddenly you're worthless and we're we
suddenly we have this bizarre thing that
other people are in fact dangerous like
we're really concerned about other
people taking our stuff yeah and then
and then we have the realm abundance
where other people are just important
for being under people and there are
always potential collaborators and we
live right on the razor's edge of that
and in the contemporary context I'm
because I'm looking at so many different
things and you know this notion of
something like a ubi construct has been
not talked about and maybe even has been
delivered in certain domains even if
it's fifteen hundred bucks one time or
whatever and I don't know if you know
this but I actually was working on that
concept 11 years ago and was proposing
it as the thing 11 years ago so I have a
lot of underlying techniques and math
and models for it
so I dusted that off about two weeks ago
I started taking a look at it and I got
to tell you right now if we chose to if
we all sort of collectively said we'd
like to do it this way we could deliver
every single person and now I'll be
talking about America cuz I did the
magic in the context of this nation
state but it applies anywhere but in USD
in the US every single person $2,500 a
month of basic income and in addition
$1,400 a month the basic health you know
there's two different constructs easily
like it isn't it actually makes
everything work better that changes a
lot right that's a very very so what I'm
saying about that is it's like it's keen
to my mind because you were talking
about in the context to have a lot of
people are about to discover that their
their jobs aren't needed and the
professions aren't needed and and that's
gonna put them in to really bad places
one place is they're going to be in
privation because we don't have a way of
giving people what they need unless
their jobs are needed yeah
and it's gonna put in a sense of
existential written dread I am NOT
needed and how do I know that I'm not
needed well I'm starving people aren't
taking care of me yeah so I've got the
fact that I feel it because my identity
just got shattered is being reinforced
by the fact that I'm actually in in
existential risk well that's on this
left-hand side if we flip to the
right-hand side which we could just do
not only are you no longer an
existential risk look we could just take
care of you it's real easy we could all
take care of each other the possibility
for doing that is very high and then by
the way we care for you and so you're
the whole reason why we're caring for is
because you're actually valuable as a
purse and thanks God you're not doing
stuff that was a waste of your life well
we don't want you to do a step that's a
waste of your life we don't need you
doing that and and that's because you're
more important than that please stop
doing things that are wasting your life
on this earth it's a very rare and
precious thing so we're gonna care for
you so you don't have to worry about it
and now we're going to try to figure out
how
help you get engaged and doing the thing
that you're here to do like we're right
there like this could happen this happen
in months if we put our minds to it ya
know and that is that is again I got a
little bit of what you were doing and I
now know if it was 11 years ago that is
a very different time than doing it now
right when David introduced it yesterday
I think about perception when you were
like actually it's not yet work but so
talk about it too much but like I love
the idea of you bi and I think that if
we did have enough people coming from
the bottom we could recreate something
very easily again a million people would
be like yes I want you be islets figure
it out let's figure out what that looks
like
let's figure out what it looks like
without our governments necessarily need
to be involved that's a little harder to
need to print the money and get that out
if it's in US dollars but there's also a
possibility that didn't exist eleven
years ago which is cryptocurrency and
none of the current crypto currencies
are the solution but something we create
together that's designed like ubi that
is designed that it's generated to and
we agree to make it an exchange between
us is something we can absolutely do
much more easily than someone coming up
with a disseminating it's everyone yeah
yeah I love my guys overran
cryptocurrency because they've solved
that first this in the second s we
haven't got to the third dish yet but
the notion that we the people could just
create our own currency done deal ten
years ago what the hell are you talking
about now obviously right yeah what's
the exact right design not quite sure
yet we've got a bunch of good people
who've been building a lot of stuff and
making good headway close ten years ago
again no idea now kind of close so just
got a little bit just got to close that
last little bit yeah no it's huge I mean
there's so much potential happening
right now because I mean I had this
concept that isn't any of the things
that I'm doing is a project necessarily
but it might be in the future which is
like there's these four questions that
I'm like if we solve them and you never
solve them but its life is about trying
to solve them and never solving them and
it's like Who am I who are my people
what is my purpose and what do I need
and at every level we solve that you get
something intrinsically valuable when
you know yourself a little bit that's a
gift when you have one friend gets you
for you that's a gift when you figure
out what you're supposed to do today for
five
and so of course I want to create the
technology that facilitates that whole
process but even just a conversation and
weekly write with five different people
where you're concentrating on Who am I
or you're concentrate on creating a
culture that people can show up in as
themselves you're concentrating on like
I might not want to sit at a table with
you but that doesn't mean you don't get
to sit at anyone's table right like
everyone's deserving of people even if
I'm not your people everyone has a place
you're worthy because you're a human
being who's alive and I know you have a
purpose and migrate your the greatest
gift you can give to me as you living
your purpose even if I don't think your
purpose is valuable right like even if I
don't see it you living it is gonna be a
much better value than whatever those
useless professions are that I don't
want you doing because they were useless
and you probably didn't feel great about
it either so I think a beautiful world
is coming it's just like this is the
chrysalis this is returning into
caterpillar goo and it's very
uncomfortable but but and some people
don't know that just like the
caterpillar doesn't know that and other
people do and it's like we live in
interesting times cope in 19 where
people who had high anxiety and I worry
about the world to some degree I feel
like my stress went down because the
rest of the world joined me like it was
like thank you right our government is
the best we have and there no way if it
is sufficient to solve these things
that's a problem on every level in every
industry and so if we leave it up to
them this is what we get
let's solve food let's solve
transportation let's solve infectious
disease in a way that we can trust and
use it and that's the generating with
green annatto yep yep yeah I'm with you
I love I love you I agree my stress
level went way down because my stress
was always super high because I was
sitting there looking this is gonna
happen is it's gonna be bad and we need
to start working on it but now I don't
have to have those conversations happen
it's bad now let's work on it can we
stop the middle to skip the beginning
part and get to the part we actually
figure it out and yeah and this is the
thing of course as you as you as we all
know if we actually kind of think about
it we can it's not like any of these
problems right
that hard and most of the problems are
already well figured out by the right
people you just kind of got to get the
right people yes get him on there
purpose which is it what they want to do
anyway yeah I saw this great video
Daniel shader on Facebook and then I
shared it again by a dr. Zee Dogg I
think look he was livid he was uh he
actually is funny he said like his full
name he said that's right when I start
with my full name you think new things
are about to get real it's like I'm just
I was just you know experiencing or
becoming aware of the fact that there
are medical doctors and nurses right now
who are being fired for doing the right
thing right for complaining about the
fact there's not adequate PPE to protect
themselves and he's like this is
done like the this corrupt system will
be burned to the ground
once this crisis is over hopefully
that's it and he sees seeing the right
thing and there's an energy behind it of
a recognition that the people who are
here he say look I'm a doctor I have a
purpose I don't think anybody has any
questions about whether my purpose is
valuable and I'm here to do the thing
yeah and everybody else has a purpose
and those purposes are valuable though
it's not obvious exactly what they are
in some cases but that's it's as kind of
as simple as that just find the people
we'll help them find their purpose
support them and doing their purpose
then connect with other people who get
it they're supposed to support them any
it ain't how I says it's simple and easy
but it's simple yes absolutely and it is
all viable all doable and I love that
like this isn't going back to normal but
this is also a boat as mild and easy an
apocalypse as I can imagine like people
are stuck at home we'll figure it out
like it's like people have time and they
have this it's like mother nature did
send us all in our room without I'm like
I could if mother nature's intelligence
this is about the most perfect
intelligent thing to do to our species
and I in no way saw it coming like
pandemics yes that we would actually
sequester ourselves in our houses for
the good of 1% of our population I
didn't think humanity would do that and
it's actually really beautiful that we
are it's amazing and well so I'll take
the responsibility of painting the other
side of the of the painting which is you
this is the most beautiful and
lightweight apocalypse we've ever faced
and I really do hope we actually get it
together and get through the chrysalis
stage and the energy that we've been
given right now because I can tell you
this if we do go back to something like
normal the next apocalypse will not be
easy no this one's on a two-week
timescale and our governments still were
like no we'll be fine oh we're not fine
it's like our climate change
environmental is on decades not two
weeks of a time scale and yeah our next
one is much worse this is our easy one
this is our kindergarten and we can do
something from here this is the one
where mom like knocks on the bedroom
door and says hey it's time to go to
sleep yeah or wake up things get yeah
time to wake up
we don't take if we don't take the note
right now if we don't listen to the
signals being very obviously sent to us
and do the thing that we actually know
we need to be doing then I guess we get
way we deserve we'll be shaking up a
little bit more abruptly next time all
right so I got to go yes thank you so
much Jordan this is a great conversation
I'll probably contact you again in six
months while the whole new world yeah
right anyone I think I tried to get any
one solution raising I don't know if
it's your thing but anyone you know the
who that's their jam I have a Facebook
group that people can join my option I I
imagined that that will be my jam in the
not-too-distant future but get away for
the for the streams to cross naturally
awesome
sounds good all right thanks Jordan okay